# Muslum Ozgur Ozmen

#### Research Interests

My research interests broadly lie in the area of systems security. Through systems design, formal verification, machine learning, and applied cryptography, my research seeks to improve security and privacy guarantees in emerging computing platforms. My research approach is best illustrated by my work in IoT safety and security. My anticipated graduation date is May 2024.

#### **EDUCATION**

JAN 2020 — PRESENT Ph.D. in Computer Science

4.00/4.00

Advisor: Prof. Z. Berkay Celik

Committee Members: Prof. Dongyan Xu, Prof. Xiangyu Zhang, Prof.

Antonio Bianchi

Purdue University West Lafayette, IN, USA

Sept 2016 — June 2018 MSc in Computer Science

3.96/4.00

Dr. Attila Altay Yavuz

Oregon State University Corvallis, OR, USA

Sept 2012 — June 2016 BS in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

3.49/4.00

Bilkent University Ankara, Turkey

#### RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Lead Graduate Student - Prof. Celik's Research Group, Purdue University 2022 - Present

- Conduct project meetings with five students
- Provide students with mentoring and research guidance

## Cyber-Physical Systems Research Intern - Toyota Research Institute North America 2023 Supervisors: Dr. Georgios Fainekos and Dr. Bardh Hoxha

- Conducted research on the security of mobile robot controllers
- Developed an optimization-guided falsification framework for control barrier function-based controllers

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## Co-Instructor:

• CS426 - Computer Security, Purdue University

Spring 2023

## **Guest Lecturer:**

• CS590 - IoT & CPS Security, Purdue University

Spring 2022

## Teaching Assistant:

• CS496 - Mobile and Cloud Software Development, Oregon State University

Winter 2018

- CS261 - Data Structures, CS/ECE578 - Cyber-security, Oregon State University

Fall 2017

• CS492 - Mobile Software Development, Oregon State University

Winter 2017

### Peer-reviewed conference publications:

- C22 Muslum Ozgur Ozmen, Ruoyu Song, Habiba Farrukh and Z. Berkay Celik. Evasion Attacks on Smart Home Physical Event Verification and Defenses. Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS) 2023. (Acceptance Rate: 16.2%)
- C21 Habiba Farrukh\*, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**\*, Kerem Ors and Z. Berkay Celik. *One Key to Rule Them All: Secure Group Pairing for Heterogeneous IoT Devices.* IEEE S&P 2023. equally contributed. (Acceptance Rate: 17%)
- C20 Muslum Ozgur Ozmen\*, Habiba Farrukh\*, Hyungsub Kim, Antonio Bianchi and Z. Berkay Celik. Rethinking Secure Pairing in Drone Swarms. VehicleSec 2023. equally contributed.
- C19 Ruoyu Song, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**, Hyungsub Kim, Raymond Muller, Z. Berkay Celik, and Antonio Bianchi. *Discovering Adversarial Driving Maneuvers against Autonomous Vehicles*. Usenix Security 2023. (Acceptance Rate: 29%)
- C18 Hyungsub Kim, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**, Z. Berkay Celik, Antonio Bianchi and Dongyan Xu. Patch Verif: Discovering Faulty Patches in Robotic Vehicles. Usenix Security 2023. (Acceptance Rate: 29%)
- C17 Khaled Serag, Rohit Bhatia, Akram Faqih, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**, Vireshwar Kumar, Z. Berkay Celik, Dongyan Xu. *ZBCAN: A Zero-Byte CAN Defense System*. Usenix Security 2023.(Acceptance Rate: 29%)
- C16 Muslum Ozgur Ozmen, Xuansong Li, Andrew Chu, Z. Berkay Celik, Bardh Hoxha and Xiangyu Zhang. *Discovering IoT Physical Channel Vulnerabilities*. ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (ACM CCS) 2022. (Acceptance Rate: 22%)
- C15 Hyungsub Kim, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**, Z. Berkay Celik, Antonio Bianchi and Dongyan Xu. *PGPATCH: Policy-Guided Logic Bug Patching for Robotic Vehicles*. IEEE S&P 2022. (Acceptance Rate: 14.5%)
- C14 Andrew Chu, Arjun Arunasalam **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen** and Z. Berkay Celik. *Behind the Tube: Exploitative Monetization of Content on YouTube*. Usenix Security 2022. (Acceptance Rate: 17.2%)
- C13 Hyungsub Kim, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**, Antonio Bianchi, Z. Berkay Celik and Dongyan Xu. *PGFUZZ: Policy-Guided Fuzzing for Robotic Vehicles*. Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS) 2021. (Acceptance Rate: 15.2%)
- C12 Furkan Goksel\*, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**\*, Michael Reeves, Basavesh Shivakumar and Z. Berkay Celik. On the Safety Implications of Misordered Events and Commands in IoT Systems. IEEE Workshop on the Internet of Safe Things (SafeThings) 2021. equally contributed.
- C11 Rouzbeh Behnia, Attila Yavuz, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen** and Tsz Hon Yuen. Compatible Certificateless and Identity-Based Cryptosystems for Heterogeneous IoT. International Conference on Information Security (ISC) 2020.
- C10 Efe U. A. Seyitoglu, Attila Yavuz and **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**. Compact and Resilient Cryptographic Tools for Digital Forensics. IEEE Conference on Communications and Network Security (IEEE CNS) 2020. (Best Paper Award Finalist)
- C9 Muslum Ozgur Ozmen, Attila Yavuz and Rouzbeh Behnia. Energy-Aware Digital Signatures for Embedded Medical Devices. IEEE Conference on Communications and Network Security (IEEE CNS) 2019.

- C8 Rouzbeh Behnia, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen** and Attila Yavuz. *ARIS: Authentication for Real-Time IoT Systems*. International Conference on Communications (IEEE ICC) 2019.
- C7 Muslum Ozgur Ozmen, Rouzbeh Behnia and Attila Yavuz. Fast Authentication from Aggregate Signatures with Improved Security. Financial Cryptography and Data Security (FC) 2019. (Acceptance Rate: 21.9%)
- C6 Rouzbeh Behnia, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**, Attila Yavuz and Mike Rosulek. *TACHYON: Fast Signatures from Compact Knapsack*. ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (ACM CCS) 2018. (Acceptance Rate: 16.6%)
- C5 Muslum Ozgur Ozmen and Attila Yavuz. Dronecrypt-An Ultra-Low Energy Cryptographic Framework for Small Aerial Drones. IEEE MILCOM 2018.
- C4 Muslum Ozgur Ozmen, Rouzbeh Behnia and Attila Yavuz. Compact Energy and Delay-Aware Authentication. IEEE Conference on Communications and Network Security (IEEE CNS) 2018.
- C3 Muslum Ozgur Ozmen, Thang Hoang and Attila Yavuz. Forward-Private Dynamic Searchable Symmetric Encryption with Efficient Search. International Conference on Communications (IEEE ICC) 2018.
- C2 Muslum Ozgur Ozmen and Attila Yavuz. Low-Cost Standard Public Key Cryptography Services for Wireless IoT Systems. Workshop on Internet of Things Security and Privacy (IoT S&P) 2017 (Affiliated with ACM CCS).
- C1 Rouzbeh Behnia, Attila Yavuz and **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**. *High-Speed High-Security Public Key Encryption with Keyword Search*. IFIP Annual Conference on Data and Applications Security and Privacy (DBSec) 2017.

## Peer-reviewed journal publications:

- J3 Attila Yavuz and **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**. *Ultra Lightweight Multiple-time Digital Signature* for the Internet of Things Devices. IEEE Transactions on Services Computing (IEEE TSC), 2019.
- J2 Thang Hoang, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**, Yeongjin Jang and Attila Yavuz. *Hardware-Supported ORAM in Effect: Practical Oblivious Search and Update on Very Large Dataset.* Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies (PoPETS), 2019. (Acceptance Rate: 22%)
- J1 Rouzbeh Behnia, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen** and Attila Yavuz. Lattice-Based Public Key Encryption with Keyword Search from Experimental Perspectives. IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing (IEEE TDSC), 2018.

### PATENTS

- P3 Rouzbeh Behnia, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen** and Attila Yavuz. *Efficient Identity-Based and Certificateless Cryptosystems*, US Patent 10,673,625
- P2 Attila Yavuz, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen** and Rouzbeh Behnia. *Energy-aware Digital Signatures*, US Patent 10,547,455
- P1 Thang Hoang, **Muslum Ozgur Ozmen**, and Attila Yavuz Forward-Private Dynamic Searchable Symmetric Encryption with Efficient Search, US Patent 10,922,273

#### **Invited Talks:**

- I2 Compositional Safety and Security Reasoning in IoT Environments. University of California Santa Cruz. Virtual, February 2023.
- I1 Lightweight, Delay-Aware and Scalable Cryptographic Services for Smart-Grid Systems. Cyber Resilient Energy Delivery Consortium (CREDC) Pacific Northwest Industry Workshop. Richland, WA, USA, November 2017.

### Conference and Workshop Talks:

- T7 Evasion Attacks on Smart Home Physical Event Verification and Defenses. Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS). San Diego, CA, USA, March 2023.
- T6 Discovering IoT Physical Channel Vulnerabilities. ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security. Los Angeles, CA, USA, November 2022.
- T5 Energy-Aware Digital Signatures for Embedded Medical Devices. IEEE Conference on Communications and Network Security. Washington, DC, USA, June 2019.
- T4 Fast Authentication from Aggregate Signatures with Improved Security. Financial Cryptography and Data Security. St Kitts and Nevis, February 2019.
- T3 TACHYON: Fast Signatures from Compact Knapsack. ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security. Toronto, ON, Canada, October 2018.
- T2 Forward-Private Dynamic Searchable Symmetric Encryption with Efficient Search. IEEE International Conference on Communications. Kansas City, MO, USA, May 2018.
- T1 Low-Cost Standard Public Key Cryptography Services for Wireless IoT Systems. Workshop on Internet of Things Security and Privacy. Dallas, TX, USA, November 2017.

#### STUDENT RESEARCH ADVISING

Ben Chen	MSc Computer Science, Purdue University	2022 - Present
Andrew Chu	BS Computer Science, Purdue University $\rightarrow$ Ph.D. University of Chicago	2020-2021
Ruoyu Song	BS Computer Science, Purdue University $\rightarrow$ Ph.D. Purdue University	2020
Furkan Goksel	BS Computer Science, METU $\rightarrow$ Picus Security	Summer 2020
Kerem Ors	BS Computer Science, Sabanci Uni $\rightarrow$ Ph.D. Purdue University	Summer 2020

#### SERVICES

#### **Program Committee Member:**

- SmartGridComm 2023
- CPSIoTSec 2023
- SafeThings 2023
- RICSS 2023

#### Reviewer:

- ACM Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT/Ubicomp) 2023
- IEEE IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics and Security 2023

- ACM Transaction on Internet of Things 2023
- IEEE Internet of Things Journal 2022
- Journal of Complex & Intelligent Systems Springer, 2021
- IEEE Transactions on Services Computing 2020
- IEEE Access 2019
- Journal of Ambient Intelligence and Humanized Computing Springer, 2018

#### **External Reviewer:**

- IEEE S&P 2023, 2024
- Usenix Security 2022, 2023, 2024
- NDSS 2022, 2023, 2024
- CCS 2021
- ACSAC 2017, 2018, 2019, 2022
- WWW 2019

### AWARDS AND HONORS

- Recipient of NDSS 2023 Travel Grant (1,550\$).
- IEEE CNS 2020 Best Paper Award Finalist
- Recipient of IEEE CNS 2019 Travel Grant (1,250\$).
- Turkish Educational Foundation, Outstanding Success Scholarship (awarded to 50 students nationwide), September 2013 June 2016.

#### References

Available on Request